女士们,先生们。你知道吗，有些人几乎每天都晒自己的照片，像我的新手表一样，拍春天的西湖，这是我在从街头到校园的演讲比赛中拍的。人们痴迷于给自己拍照。
ladies and gentlemen. do you know people who post pictures of themselves almost every day snap like my new watch snap west lake in spring and snap here's me middle of a speech competition from streets to campuses. people are obsessed with taking photos of themselves.
但当摄影术在19世纪第一次传入中国时，它给一代人造成了创伤。
but when photography was first introduced to china in nineteenth century, it traumatized a generation.
用一个炮形的拉炮管，把耀眼的烟花暴露在那样的阳光下。
with a draw tube shaped like a cannon, the dazzling firework at exposure like that.
最可怕的是她自己的脸在一张纸上盯着你的奇怪感觉。
and most horrifying of all the bizarre feeling of her own face staring back at you on a piece of paper and.
巫术，他们说一种邪恶的仪式带走了我们的灵魂。
witchcraft, they say an evil ritual taken away our spirits.
随着技术的发展，历史的意志也在前进。
as the development of technology moves, the will of history forward.
它总是伴随着恐惧。
it was always accompanied by fear.
回顾自拍热的时代，当然是这样。如果你不是你自己，我们会想要告诉那些愚昧的人过去的。不会被相机吸进去这正是我想告诉人们的关于当下的恐惧，不是因为当技术革新我们的生活时，人性会被定格。
judging in retrospect from the era of selfie craze, of course. we would want to tell those benighted people of the past if you're not yourself. won't be sucked into a camera and this is exactly what i want to tell people of the present fear, not because when technology revolutionize our lives, humanity frames.
看看我们现在的世界。
look at our world now.
科学家和人文主义者之间的争论似乎永远不会让我们的头脑放松下来，当科学家们吹嘘说可以概括560克时。人类说你提供了侵犯个人隐私的简单方法。
the debate between scientists and humanists never seem to set our minds at rest when scientists are bragging about generalizing five g sixty. the humans say you're providing easy ways to infringe on personal privacy.
当科学家。
when scientists.
吹嘘人工智能是人类的终极助手。
brag the ai as humans ultimate assistant.
民间作家说我们是他们发展自己意识的地方。
the civil writer say we're where they might develop consciousness of their own.
有一次我自称，一个物理学家跟我的人文学学院的能力谈过关于瞬间传送的问题理论上我们可以把任何东西从这里传送到那里通过分解这里的东西然后在那里重建一个相同的东西，但我马上就被轰炸了你这么快就要用这种方式传送人了，对吧。
once i a self proclaimed, the physicist talked to my powers from the school of humanities about teleportation is that theoretically we can transport anything from here to there instantly by disintegrating the stuff here and reconstructing an identical one there, but i was instantly bombarded with so soon you are going to transport people in this way, would you.
但传送之后我们就不是原来的那个人了。我的意识会不会在这里瞬间瓦解，只留下一个我的复制品在那里重建无辜的旁观者一听到这些荒诞的辩论就惊慌失措哦，不，鹅要读我们的饭了。机器人将从地球上起飞。
but we won't be the same person after teleport. will my consciousness be instantly terminated upon disintegration here, leaving only a duplicate of me to be reconstructed there so innocent bystanders upon hearing these fantastic debates panic oh no, the geese are going to read our meals. the robots are going to take off the earth.
瞬间移动每天会摧毁成千上万的人，留下一堆衣服。
teleportation is going to destroy thousands of people every day, leaving a word full of clothes.
但这些都不是。
but none of this.
是会发生的。
is actually going to happen.
因为人文主义者不是危言耸听者，科学家也不是极客。
because humanists are not alarmists and scientists are not geeks.
人文主义者指出部分和伦理问题，希望加以纠正;科学家理性听取他们的建议，进行调整和修正。
humanists point out part and ethical issues with the hope of correcting them, and scientists listen to their suggestions rationally to make adjustments as well as amendments.
就像第一个改进相机使它不那么可怕的先驱一样，我们总是可以用人道主义关怀来改善技术。
just like the first pioneer who modified the camera to make it less scary, we can always improve technology with humanitarian care.
我们可以通过引入量子密码来增强网络的安全性。
we can enhance the security of networks by introducing quantum cryptography.
我们可以对人工智能进行限制，以防止不法分子进行远程传送，或者运送人类可能太冒险了，但我们仍然可以通过管理配送系统来减轻北京交通的相当大的负担。
we can put restrictions on a.i. to prevent rogue elements as for teleportation or maybe it's too risky to transport humans, but we can still relieve a considerable burden of beijing traffic by taking care of the delivery system.
让我们来看看未来。我到底看到了什么。
so taking a glimpse into the future. what exactly do i see.
而不是人类沦为奴隶的ai rain反乌托邦。而不是核战争后的末日沙漠。
not the ai rain dystopia where humans are reduced to slaves. not the post apocalypse desert after a nuclear war.
但在未来，人类以科技为成功的工具，科技以人类为行为准则而蓬勃发展。就像我们推销十九世纪的人们在镜头前感到恐惧一样，我们的后代也在想，当他们达到前所未有的高维度和跨越星辰的罗马时，我们为什么一开始会害怕他们的一些日常生活。谢谢你！
but a future where humanity thrive with technology as its instrument of success and technologies right with humanity as its code of conduct. just like how we market nineteenth century people for being fearful in front of a camera, our future generations were also we wondering why we had feared some of their daily routines in the first place as they reach ever high dimensions and rome across the stars. thank you.
认为你的选手。
think your contestant.